Guide to the AIDS/Brookyn Oral History Project collection 1993.001
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Sandoval, William with Rodriguez, Rita, 1992 June 11; 1993.001.18
  When interviewed in 1992, Willie Sandoval was a forty-one year old Latino person with AIDS who became infected with the HIV virus through IV drug use. He was one of nine siblings (six sons and three daughters) who witnessed and was subjected to his father's frequent episodes of domestic violence and alcoholism. A resident of Brooklyn's Sunset Park neighborhood as an adult, he was diagnosed in 1988 after being hospitalized for a series of illnesses and psychiatric episodes associated with AIDS. Sandoval then lived at his sister's home in the Kensington neighborhood of Brooklyn, but by 1992, he was often staying in the Lutheran Medical Center's AIDS ward. Sandoval worked with a number of organizations (ACT UP, GMHC, church and education groups) in which he was very active. This community and activist work had to be curtailed because of his health. Brooklyn, as a place to live and as a way of life, was very important to Sandoval. He died on September 26, 1992 of complications due to AIDS. His sister, Rita Rodriguez, was forty-three at the time of the interview, and moved out of Brooklyn in 1993.
  In the interview, Willie Sandoval speaks of the spread of the epidemic through particular Brooklyn neighborhoods--mainly Sunset Park--with an insider's knowledge. His extensive experience in AIDS organizations make it possible for him to draw comparisons between Brooklyn and other parts of the city; ergo he makes some observations about the differences in attitude between Brooklyn and Manhattan physicians dealing with people with AIDS. Sandoval and Rita Rodriguez recall their difficult upbringing, Sandoval's descent into habitual drug abuse, the trauma he caused to family and how family has responded to his illness. They discuss how treatment can be improved and how awareness can address the stigma associated with the virus. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  ACT UP New York (Organization).; Gay Men's Health Crisis, Inc.; Lutheran Hospital (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).; AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS activists |z New York (State) |z New York; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Drug addiction |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Family life |z New York (State) |z Kings County; HIV infections |z New York (State) |z New York; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Self-help groups |z New York (State) |z New York; Social group work |z New York (State); South Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)
- Sepkowitz, Douglas, 1992 October 23; 1993.001.19
  Born in Oklahoma, Dr. Douglas Sepkowtiz is an infectious disease specialist who, after studying internal medicine at medical school, witnessed the AIDS crisis firsthand while working in Brooklyn's emergency rooms and Maimonides Medical Center in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. HIV impacted his work and his personal life; having a colleague who was living with HIV and losing a close family member as a result of HIV/AIDS. The narrator has published widely in medical journals and in 2016, is also an Assistant Professor of Medicine at SUNY -Downstate College of Medicine.
  In the interview, Dr. Sepkowitz discusses his experience as a doctor in Brooklyn during the AIDS crisis. Throughout, the narrator brings up issues of ethics and humanity as a medical service provider; focusing on medical professionals gossiping about modes of transmission of their patients, and patients' agency in making decisions around care. He also discusses what changed as the epidemic evolved; including the populations of the patients he saw and structural changes within the world of medicine. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  ACT UP New York (Organization).; Maimonides Hospital of Brooklyn.; AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS activists |z New York (State) |z New York; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Family life |z New York (State) |z Kings County; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Medicaid; Physicians |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Sexual health |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Social group work |z New York (State); Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Terson, Alice, 1992 September 26; 1993.001.20
  Alice Terson was an HIV positive Latina lesbian born in 1952. At the time of the interview in 1992, she was a mother of one son and had a female partner. She was in recovery and had been formerly incarcerated. She worked at an AIDS service organization in Manhattan while living in Brooklyn, where she had friends and a sense of community. Alice Terson died in 2009.
  In the interview, Alice Terson shares her personal experience living with HIV and providing care and services for others living with HIV. Early in the interview, she speaks about her adulthood and how she had to overcome the negative stereotypes associated with the various aspects of who she was: lesbian, female, Latina, former drug user, formerly incarcerated, Spanish speaker. Self-identifying first as advocate, then as activist, the narrator speaks with passion about the holes in the system as she sees them, including but not limited to; the ways doctors need to build trust with patients, how prisons need to have HIV awareness and prevention programs, and the need for more Brooklyn-based services for folks living with HIV. Interview conducted by Robert Sember.
  Gay Men's Health Crisis, Inc.; Riker's Island (N.Y.).; AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS activists |z New York (State) |z New York; AZT (Drug); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Gay culture |z New York (State) |z New York; HIV infections |z New York (State) |z New York; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Immunological deficiency syndromes; Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Self-help groups |z New York (State) |z New York
- Weinstein, Ivan Keith, 1992 April 4; 1993.001.21
  Ivan Keith Weinstein was a partnered, thirty-year-old, gay man living with HIV in the Flatbush neighborhood of Brooklyn at the time of this 1992 interview. Before he entered into what he called “forced retirement,” due to his health, Weinstein was in the security industry. Afterwards, he worked a lot within the community, specifically as a stage manager for the AIDS Theater Project. Ivan Keith Weinstein died circa 1992.
  In the interview, Ivan Keith Weinstein discusses his experience as a partnered gay man living with HIV in Brooklyn in the early 1990s. He covers the difference for him in what it means to be living with HIV vs. getting an AIDS diagnosis; the choices he had to make about dis-closure with his friends and family on account of his partner’s comfort level; the lack of good services for people living with HIV in Brooklyn; and the impact that living with HIV has had on his personal relationships, his work, sex life, and engagement with the medical profession. Towards the end of the interview, a different interviewer comes in and prompts the narrator to discuss the first person he knew with HIV in Brooklyn and the differences in stigma and care in Manhattan versus Brooklyn. Interview conducted by Robert Rosenberg.
  AIDS Theatre Project.; AIDS (Disease) |x Information services; AIDS (Disease) |x Patients |x Services for |z New York (State) |z New York; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Family life |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Flatbush (New York, N.Y.); HIV infections |z New York (State) |z New York; HIV-positive persons |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Sexual health |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Social group work |z New York (State); Stigma (Social psychology) |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Theater |z New York (State) |z New York
- Series 2: Oral History Transcripts
  This series includes transcripts of interviews with Barbara Norris, Mildred Pearson, Kenny Post and Cheryl Wagner, Dolores Rivera, Luis E. Nieves Rosa, and William Sanoval with Rita Rodriguez, and are arranged arbitrarily. Transcripts, as well as interview abstracts in the "Summaries" folder, are located in box 1. Contents of box 1 were inventoried and remain unprocessed.
- Series 3: Research Materials
  Made from what was gathered and generated through the oral history project and exhibition, the materials relate directly to the AIDS epidemic in Brooklyn, as well as to AIDS/HIV in the New York metropolitan area. This series includes magazines, books, pamphlets, articles, biographies, a radio program and resource lists. Subjects concern AIDS information in Spanish, AIDS resources, support services, food services, educational material, legal information, discrimination, hemophilia, and children and teens. The research materials are largely unprocessed, separated by subject matter or format, arranged arbitrarily, and located in three boxes and one binder.
- Interview on WEBE Radio, 1988; 1993.001.22
  A gay man, Drew was thirty-two years old at the time of the interview in 1988 and had been living with HIV for almost two years. He was not on medication and identified himself as asymptomatic. His partner of seven years, Donald, died on their anniversary. Minna, a straight, HIV-negative woman, was married to Victor, a hemophiliac who had recently died of AIDS-related causes. (Within the AIDS/Brooklyn Oral History Project, Minna is known as Melinda Broman.)
  Access to the recording is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. Use of the audio recordings other than for private study, scholarship, or research requires the permission of BHS. For assistance, contact library@brooklynhistory.org.
  This radio program (WEBE 108 Radio) begins with interviews--first with Drew, then Minna--about the loss of partners due to HIV/AIDS, and concludes with information on the most up to date medical advancements and applications, circa 1988. In their interviews, Drew and Minna discuss the death of their partners, their own physical health, any family and community support they had and have, and their thoughts and feelings about the epidemic. The host of the program is Pamela Easton.
  AIDS (Disease) |z New York (State) |z New York; AIDS activists |z United States; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Gay culture |z New York (State) |z New York; Gays |x Social life and customs; Hemophiliacs |z New York (State) |z Kings County; HIV infections |z New York (State) |z New York; Immunological deficiency syndromes; Marriage customs and rites |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Self-help groups |z New York (State) |z New York
- Series 4: Magnetic Tapes
  Consists of oral history interview recordings on original videotape and audiotape recordings and duplicate audiotape recordings. The oral history tapes are labeled with narrator names and interview dates, and arranged by duplicates and originals in two boxes in an arbitrary order. Unprocessed.